

# (Short CV) - Cláudio Finkelstein (LL.M.; Ph.D.; FCIArb)

Bachelor's degree in Law from Pontifícia Universidade Católica de São Paulo (1989), LL.M in International Law from the University of Miami (1991), Ph.d. in Law from Pontifícia Universidade Católica de São Paulo (2000) and Full Tenure (Livre-Docência) from Pontifícia Universidade Católica de São Paulo (2011). He is currently a Professor at Pontifícia Universidade Católica de São Paulo, at both Graduate and Post Graduate levels, where he coordinates the Post Graduate Studies International Law Department. Cláudio is also the Director of the Brazilian Institute of Constitutional Law and Nacional Institute of Economic Disputes and the Vice-President of Brazilian Society of International Law. Former Coordinator of the International Contracts Course at COGEAE and Fundação Getúlio Vargas/SP. Current Coordinator of International Contracts Course at IICS. Advisor for TCC, Scientific Initiation, Master and Doctorate Programs at Pontifícia Universidade Católica de São Paulo. Arbitrator. His practice focuses on Private and Public International law, especially: International Law and Arbitration.

## A. PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Full name: Cláudio Finkelstein

Name used in Bibliographic Citations: FINKELSTEIN, C:

Gender: Male:

Parental information: José Morisso Finkelstein and Raquel Finkelstein;

Birth information: 12/02/1964 - São Paulo/SP – Brazil; Identification document: 99001509 SSP - SP - 28/12/1979;

CPF Number: 107.263.418-00;

Address: Praça Amadeu Amaral, 27 – Bela Vista.

São Paulo - 01327-010, SP - Brazil;

Phone: +55 11 32530151

E-Mail: Contact e-mail: claudio@finkelstein.com.br

Alternative e-mail: cfinkelstein@pucsp.br

# B. FORMAL EDUCATION:

## Tenure

Pontifícia Universidade Católica de São Paulo, PUC/SP, Sao Paulo, Brazil Title: *Jus Cogens como Paradigma do Metaconstitucionalismo de Direito Internacional (Jus Cogens* as a paradigm for a metaconstitucionalism in

International Law), Year of degree: 2011

Keywords: Hierarguy of Law, International Law

Knowledge areas: Law

Year: 2011



Doctorate in Law (Ph.D.)

Pontifícia Universidade Católica de São Paulo, PUC/SP, Sao Paulo, Brazil Title: O Processo de Formação de Mercado de Blocos (The Procedure for

Trade Block Creation), Year of degree: 2000

Advisor: Celso RIbeiro Bastos

Scholarship from: Coordenação de Aperfeiçoamento de Pessoal de Nível

Superior

Year: 1994 - 2000

Master's in International Law

University of Miami, MIAMI, Coral Gables, United States

Title: Mercosul, an attempt, Year of degree: 1991

Advisor: Thomas Murphy

Scholarship from: Coordenação de Aperfeiçoamento de Pessoal de Nível

Superior

Year: 1990 - 1991

Bachelor's degree in Law

Pontifícia Universidade Católica de São Paulo, PUC/SP, Sao Paulo, Brazil

Year: 1984 - 1989

#### C. COMPLEMENTARY EDUCATION:

Short Term Course in Law.

Instituto Brasileiro de Estudos das Relações de Concorrência e de Consumo, IBRAC, Brazil

Year: 2002 - 2002

Short Term Course in O Direito Bras. e os Desafios da Econ. Globalizada.

Academia Internacional de Direito e Economia, AIDE, Brazil

Year: 2002 - 2002

#### D. PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

# a. Arbitrator

In the roaster of CAM-CCBC; FIESP and various other Brazilian Arbitration Chambers.

#### b. Academic

Pontifícia Universidade Católica de São Paulo - PUC/SP

#### Contract institutional



Contract: Post Graduation - Coordinator Law School and International Relations School - Professor - Position: Professor and advisor, Working hours (weekly):

40,

Scheme of job: Full-time Year: 2001 – Current

#### **Activities**

Research and Development, School of Law

Year: 02/2001 - Current

Post-graduate degree, Law Year: 02/2001 – Current

Subjects Taught:
Public International Law
Private International Law
International Trade
International Arbitration

2. Fundação Getúlio Vargas - SP - FGV-SP

# **Contract institutional**

Contract: Collaborator, Position: course coordinator, Working hours (weekly):

10.

Scheme of job: Part-time

Year: 2007 - 2009

3. IICS - Instituto Internacional de Ciências Sociais IICS-SP

#### Contract institutional

Contract: Collaborator, Position: course coordinator – title International

Contracts,

Working hours (weekly): 10, Scheme of job: Part-time

Year: 2013

4. University of Miami – FLA - USA

### Contract institutional

Praça Amadeu Amaral, 27, Cj. 112 - 11º Andar Bela Vista - São Paulo - SP - 01327-010 Tel: (+55 11) 3253-0151 / 3266-6352 / 3266-6378



Contract: Professor Position: assistant course coordinator (Basics of

International

Arbitration for Brazilian Students), Working hours (week long extention course),

Schemes of job: Part-time

Year: 2013 - 2014

5. Fordham University - NY - USA.

#### Contract institutional

Contract: Visiting Scholar, Position: Visiting Scholar, Working hours (weekly):

40,

Scheme of job: Full-time

Year: 2008 - 2008

6. Faculdades Integradas Rio Branco

#### **Contract institutional**

Contract: Professor, Position: Professor, Working hours (weekly): 8,

Scheme of job: Part-time

Year: 2003 - 2003

### **Activities**

Post-graduate degree, Law 02/2003 - 06/2003

Subjects Taught: International Economic Law Hierarchy of Sources in International Law

For further information please contact me.